Come on! Keep walking!
おう
Quit dragging your feet!
しっかり歩け
もたもたすんな
こらーっ！
ぐわあっ
Hey, what's the matter?
おい どうした
Let's go!
行くぞお
Those guys are getting away!
奴ら 逃げてくぞ
The victory is ours, people of Karulawaturei!
我ら カルラゥアツゥレイの勝利だ
-おおおおおお　アッハハハハハ
-いえーい　やったあ　おらあ
-ふんふん　ふんふん
-スオンカス様
Suonkasu-sama!
I bring word!
報告いたします
The slaves that were being transported were
retaken after an attack by the rebel army.
運搬中のケナムが
反乱軍の襲撃を受け 奪還されました
Prepare for battle at once.
すぐに掃討の準備をなさい
Yes, sir!
Everything is set to welcome you.
あなたを迎える準備は出来たわ
Come, hurry to my side.
さあ
早く私のもとに いらっしゃい
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dream I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は　色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn to my heart's desire
omou mama kaki suberasete
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
思うまま書き滑らせて
描く未来へとつながる
egaku mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future i draw.
Utawarerumono
sumiwataru sora
The clear skies
澄み渡る空　果てしないほど青く
hateshinai hodo aoku
were endlessly blue.
mujaki na kokoro ni
And my innocent heart,
無邪気な心に　充たされ魅かれてく
mitasare hikareteku
being satisfied, was attracted to them.
yagate jiyuu ni tobimawareru
I finally obtained wings
やがて自由に飛びまわれる
翼(はね)を手に入れて
hane wo teni irete
with which I could fly freely.
muku na hitomi wa motometeku
I want to go to the end of the skies
無垢な瞳は求めてく
空の向こうへ　行きたいな
sora no mukou he ikitai na
which my pure eyes desire.
kore tonai negai kara
If one wish could be granted
止め処ない願いから　一つだけ叶うのなら
hitotsu dake kanau no nara
out of countless others...
dare ni mo yuzuri taku wa nai
I feel that it should be to grab onto a dream
誰にも譲りたくはない
夢を掴みたいと思うよ
yume wo tsukamitai to omou yo
and never be tempted to let go.
kodomo no goro no yume wa
The dreams I had when I was a child,
子供の頃の夢は　色褪せない落書きで
iroase nai rakugaki de
were drawn eternally,
itsuwademo kaki tsuzukerareta
with scribbles that wouldn't fade away
いつまでも描き続けられた
願う未来へとつながる
negau mirai he to tsunagaru
and are connected to the future I wish for.
The Rebel Army
はむ うむ んん
You're amazing, Aru-chan.
アルちゃん
すごい
My lord...
若様
My lord!
お兄様？
Brother?
Do you dislike any of this food?
嫌いな食べ物があるのですか？
No, no, not at all!
いやいや そんなことはないぞ
あむ うっ あむっ んっ んっ
ああっ あっ 若様
My lord!
He still has much to learn.
まだまだですね
Say, Touka-san... There is no poison in there.
あの トウカさん
毒とか入ってませんから
Sorry, I must check everything that
enters His Majesty's mouth!
いえ 聖上の口に入る物は 某が
ひい
アハハ
Benawi-sama...
ベナウィ様
ご苦労様です
Good work.
Has anything happened?
何かあったのか
It's Na Tuunk...
ナトゥンクで
ケナムたちが反乱を起こしたようです
It seems the slaves have staged a rebellion.
ナトゥンク？
Na Tuunk...
Is that not where Karula is from?
確か カルラが元々いた
It seems the leader of the rebel army
is a man named Delihourai.
反乱軍を率いているのは
デリホウライという男のようですが
However, as the lack of supplies worsens,
the rebel troops are dwindling.
物資の不足が深刻なため
徐々に反乱軍は劣勢になっているとのことです
I have come here to make a humble request.
お願いがあり 参りました
Clothing certainly makes a difference
in your appearance.
着物一つで 変わるものだな
I came to make a request.
It was only proper that I dress formally.
お願いに来たのですし
正装をするのが礼儀というものですわ
It is about Na Tuunk.
ナトゥンクか
Now that's cutting to the chase.
話が早いですわね
If there were anything I could do, I would, but...
出来ることなら なんとかしてやりたい
しかし
I cannot allow this country to be
caught up in another war.
そのためにこの国を
戦火に巻き込むことは出来ない
Of course, I wouldn't ask you
to do anything for free.
もちろん ただなんて
虫のいいことは言いませんわ
Then, what do you propose?
では どうするというのだ
I will give you all I have.
私の全てを差し上げますわ
All you have?
全てを？
Yes, from a strand of hair to
the last drop of my blood.
髪の毛1本から血の1滴に至るまで
And my soul as well...
そして この魂を
To a contract with Witsalnemitea...
ウィツァルネミテアの契約を
Do you realize what you are saying?
自分が 何を言っているのか
分かっているのか？
Yes...
Then, if I told you to die, would you?
では　私が死ねと言えば死ねるのか
If that is the wish of my master.
それが 主さまのお望みとあれば
All right, if you are prepared to go that far,
I shall grant your wish.
いいだろう
そこまでの覚悟があるのなら
その望み 叶えよう
ふう 契約 成立ですわね
Then we have our contract.
No, it is nothing like that.
いやあ そんなものは関係なくだな
I have not come asking for charity.
ただで恵んでもらおうとは
思っていませんわ
What do you think you're doing?
何をするつもりだ
Can't you see?
見て分かりませんか？
I just said I would give myself
to you, body and soul.
先ほど 身も心もささげると言いましたわ
Pardon me... Hakuoro-san?
失礼します
ハクオロさ
Eruruu, may I have some tea?
エルルゥ
お茶をくれないか
Eruruu...
エルルゥ
あの
Shall I help you?
手伝おうか
や やあ
H... Hi...
Huh?
あ あれ？
I get the feeling Eruruu has
been avoiding me.
最近どうも
エルルゥに避けられてる気がする
Do you have any idea why that might be?
何か心当たりがあるのですか？
I have no idea...
全く無い
why she should not.
わけでも無いか　はあ
Commander!
総大将
Kurou, how were things?
クロウ 様子はどうだった？
To be honest, the outlook is bleak.
ういす
正直 旗色はかなり悪いです
They're pretty much being
routed at the moment.
今ではほとんど敗走状態で
It's probably only a matter of time
before they are crushed.
潰されるのは
時間の問題じゃないでしょうか
Thank you for your efforts.
You are dismissed.
ご苦労だった
下がってくれ
Sire...
ういっす
Karula, it is as you heard.
I can do nothing more.
カルラ
聞いての通りだ
これ以上の介入は
Yes, I understand.
分かっていますわ
Do you?
そうか
あ 身動きが取れん
I can't move!
Oh? Are you awake already?
あら
もうお目覚めになりましたの？
Karula! What are you...
カルラ
これは一体
We're going on a little journey.
ちょっと旅行に
A journey?
旅行？
To Na Tuunk!?
ナトゥンクか
You must be quiet at night.
夜は静かにするものですわ
So, you are going?
やはり
行かれるのですか？
You guessed it, did you?
気付いていましたのね
Karula, I am this country's mediator.
カルラ
私は この国のヨモルです
Can you appreciate my predicament?
分かってもらえますか？
I guess it can't be helped.
仕方ありませんわね
Thank goodness, I'm saved.
やれやれ 助かったか
Well, shall we be off?
それでは 参りましょうか
Why is this happening?
なぜそうなる？
What's going on at this hour?
こんな時間に どうしたんですか？
We're going on a journey.
旅行に行くんですよ
A journey?
旅行
あっ あ
ちょ ちょっと待っててください
Just a minute...
No, that's not it...
いや そうじゃなくて
Oh, Aruruu!
あら アルルゥ
Father, what are you playing?
お父さん 何遊んでる？
We are all going on a journey.
皆で旅行に行くのよ
A journey?
旅行？
I'm coming!
行く
グルゥ
Yuzu-cchi and Camus-cchi too.
ユズっち カミュっち 一緒
Everyone's going on a journey.
This sounds like fun.
皆で旅行 楽しそう
I shall accompany you.
某も お供させていただきます
んっふっ んっ お待たせしました
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Well, then, shall we be on our way?
それでは 出発しましょうか
Yes!
はーい
もう 勝手にしてくれ
I give up... Do what you will with me!
Princess!
姫さまあ
Yuzuha!
ユーズーハー
ベナウィ
Benawi, Yuzuha has...
ユズハが
The Princess has...
姫様が
He got away, he got away, he got away,
he got away, he got away...
逃げられた
逃げられた 逃げられた
-グルウウウウ
-ヒャッホー フッ
キュウキュウ
キュウ
Come here a minute, Karula.
カルラ
ちょっと
Eruruu-sama?
エルルゥ様
Yes?
はい
It's a beautiful day, isn't it?
いい お天気ですね
Huh? Yes, it is.
ああ そうだな
The mountains around here
are so high, aren't they?
こ この辺りの山は高いですね
Yes...
The ground is uneven, isn't it?
じ 地面がでこぼこしてますね
I guess...
まあな
- Recently...
- Eruruu...
-最近
-エルルゥ
It was a misunderstanding.
あれは誤解だ
Huh? I don't know what...
私 誤解なんて
That night, Karula asked me to send
reinforcements to Na Tuunk.
あの晩 カルラにナトゥンクへの
支援を頼まれたんだ
She was a little overbearing,
but I did not do anything.
フッ　少々強引ではあったが
特に何もしていないし
And neither did she.
されてもいない
Is that right?
そうですか
Oh, but I didn't...
でも 私別に
I did not want someone precious to me
to remain under a misconception.
大切な人に
誤解されたままではいたくないんでな
Precious...
大切
Yes, Eruruu, you are a precious
member of my family.
エルルゥは私にとって
大切な家族だからな
ウフ
Yes!
はい
-グルウ
-ああっ
Aruruu!
アルルゥ
ウフ
フンフン フン
-ハハ
-ウフッ
-グルルルルル
-ムックル？
Mukkuru...
-グルルルルル
-どうした
What's wrong?
We are surrounded.
囲まれております
So it appears.
そのようですわね
Eruruu, get inside!
エルルゥ 中へ
あっ はい
All right.
Wait, Touka.
待てトウカ
My name is Delihourai.
俺の名はデリホウライ
I lead the rebel army of Karulawaturei.
反軍 カルラゥアツゥレイを率いる者だ
Karulawaturei?
カルラゥアツゥレイ
Who the hell are you all?
貴様らは一体何者だ
We make our living through battle,
and were on a journey.
私たちは戦を生業とし
旅をしている者です
We heard that there was fighting in this area,
and we thought we'd sell our strength to you.
この辺りで戦いがあると聞き
あなたがたに
腕を買ってもらおうと思ったわけです
So you are mercenaries?
アンクアムというわけか
Well, this is our battle!
だがこれは我々の戦いだ
We have no use for anyone we don't know!
素性の知れぬ輩の出る幕では無い
ふん　すう
So, what will you do?
Your little brother says he needs no help.
さてどうする？
お前の弟は 助けはいらないとのことだが
No disagreement from you?
やはり否定しないか
What do you want!?
何用だ
It's all right, Touka.
大丈夫だトウカ
But...
しかし
It has been a long while, Katumau.
久しぶりですわね
カトゥマウ
So you are Karulawaturei-sama...
やはり カルラゥアツゥレイ様でしたか
It is wonderful to see you again.
お久しゅうございます
You kept your promise, didn't you?
約束を守ってくれましたわね
That child has come a long way.
あの子をあそこまで
I am truly grateful.
本当に感謝していますわ
ああ　ありがたきお言葉
I thank you for your kind words.
私めには勿体のうございます
You are too kind.
うっ さあ
デリホウライ様にもこのことを
Come, you must tell Delihourai-sama!
な 何故にございますか
But why?
The woman called Karulawaturei
no longer exists in this world.
カルラウアツゥレイという女性は
もうこの世にはいませんの
I am just an ordinary woman
called Karula now.
今の私はカルラという名の ただの女
What is that?
あれは
It cannot be!
まさか
Kill them! Don't miss a single one!
殺せえ
１人も逃すなあ
ぬうっ
くっ　なぜここが
How did they find us!?
Tamua?
タムァ？
Good work.
ご苦労だったな
You didn't!
貴様まさか
Y... You promised, let me see
my wife and child!
や 約束だ
妻と子に会わせてくれ
Oh, that's right, I'll let you see them.
ああ そうだったな
会わせてやるよ
-コトゥアハムルで待っている
-あ ああ あ
They're waiting for you in Hell,
your wife and child.
妻と子にな
Tamua!
タムァ
Kill them!
殺せえ！
フッ 面白い
Bring it on!
うううはあああああ
ぬわあっ
ぐわっ
Huh?
Wh... What's going on!?
ぬおっ　なっ 何だ？
ひ ひけえ
Retreat!
Tamua, hang on!
タムァ しっかりするのだ
Katumau-sama...
カトゥマウ 様
I just...
私は ただ
My wife... and child...
妻と 子に
Tamua!
The fool...
愚かな男だ
A traitor deserves a miserable end.
裏切り者には
それ相応の末路しか無いものを
You scum! How dare you
speak so of the dead!?
貴様 死者に対してなんて
ん？　ぐうっ
Oh, I'm sorry, my hand slipped.
あらごめんなさい
手が滑りましたわ
んっ き 貴様
Why you...
You're a small man. I can see
why you were betrayed.
小さな男
裏切られて当然ですわね
What did you say!?
何だと？
Have you ever considered things from
the standpoint of a weaker person?
あなた 少しでも弱い者の立場で
ものを考えたことがありまして？
ハッ ギリヤギナの俺が
どうして弱い者の立場で考えねばならぬ
I am a Giriyagina!
Why should I have to consider things
from a weakling's perspective?
A Giriyagina?
ギリヤギナね
They were so powerful that they never troubled
themselves to learn the problems of the weak.
その強さゆえに
弱い者の痛みを知ろうともしなかった
Such an arrogant people...
高慢な一族
That is precisely the reason they died out.
そして だからこそ滅んだ者たち
You may be one of the last, but you're
still a Giriyagina, aren't you!?
ちっ 貴様も末席とはいえ
ギリヤギナに位置する者だろう
I won't allow you to insult us any further!
それ以上の侮辱は許さんぞ
It seems I can't get through
to you with words.
どうやら
口で言っても分からないようですわね
So in that case, I'll just have to
give you a physical lesson
ならば体で教えてあげますわ
in how the weak feel.
弱い者の気持ちというものを
Interesting, you mean to fight me?
面白い
このデリホウライと戦うというのか
What's the matter?
Why don't you take up a stance?
どうした
なぜ構えない
You really don't know anything, do you?
本当に何も知りませんのね
What?
何？
Giriyagina do not assume fighting
stances or the like.
ギリヤギナに構えなどありませんのに
ながっ くっ
Karula...
カルラ
Or rather, mercenaries sent by our god...
いえ
旅のアンクアムのお方たち
Please lend us your strength!
どうか 私どもに
そのお力をお貸しください
Katu!?
カトゥ うう
I can stand on my own!
立つくらいは一人で出来る
Delihourai-sama...
デリホウライ様
Leave me alone!
構うな
ンッフッフッフ
ンッフッフッフッフッフッフ
She has finally returned to me.
ついに私のもとに帰ってきたのね
Karula, my love...
カルラ
私の愛しい人
炎さえも凍てついた
honou sae mo itetsuita
I seek the solitude
kokuno naka moto mu
that freezes even flames.
孤独の中求む
tamashi kara musubitsuki
Connecting with your soul,
魂から結びつき　私を恋い温めて
watashi wo koi atatamete
warm me with your love.
a inori no kotoba ga furue
Ah...the words of prayer tremble...
嗚呼　祈りの言葉がふるえ
a yowaki no chika kiete mo
Ah even if the faint-hearted
were to disappear...
嗚呼　弱きいのちが消えても
kurikaesu innen no nagare tadori
Following the recurring paths of fate.
くりかえす　輪廻の流れ辿り
owaranai sekai no shukumei wo mitsumeteru
I gaze upon the never-ending world's destiny.
終わらない世界の宿命を見つめてる
kurikaeshi utawareru mono tachi yo
Oh the ones being sung continuously
くりかえし　詠われる者達よ
mamorarete madoromu you ni
be protected and sleep.
守られてまどろむ宵
Farewells